we have seen amd's law let's talk about
what it implies for our
improvements so our amd's law says that
speed up is equal to 1 over 1 minus
fraction enhanced this is the part of
the program that we didn't enhance and
it just figures here plus the fraction
that we did enhance and that fraction
became so much faster because of the
speed up on that part so now let's
compare two possible enhancements
this is the first enhancement this will
be the second enhancement the first
enhancement is giving us a speed up of
20 which is an extremely large speed up
on 10% of execution time enhancement to
is giving us a speed up of
1.6 on 80% of execution time using amd's
law we can now compute what is the
overall speed up resulting from these
enhancements here we have 1 over
unaffected is 90% of execution time
affected is 0.1 and it's shorter by 20
times you can compute this and get
1.15 here we get 1 over the unenhanced
fraction is 0.2 the enhanced fraction is
0.8 and we speed that up by 1.6 factor
and we get
1.43 as you can see it is usually better
to have a smaller speed up on most of
your execution time than a huge speed up
on a very small part of it in fact even
if we had an infinite speed up on this
10% of execution time we would get 1
over unenhanced 0.9 and Hast is 0.1
divided by Infinity so it becomes zero
and we still get
1.111 now it is very very difficult to
get huge speed UPS like this on anything
and it's of course impossible to get
infinite speed UPS so what this means is
that if you put significant effort to
speed up something that is a small part
of the execution time you will still not
get a very large overall Improvement in
contrast if you're affecting a large
part of execution time then even a
reasonably small speed up will still
result in a similar speed up overall so
the overall conclusion from this is that
amd's law tells us to make the common
case fast whatever spends the most of
our execution time is what should we be
trying to speed up and we should not
focus too much on stuff that consumes
very little of our execution time